A Guide to the Papers of Albert Erskine, 1930-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Miscellaneous Authors
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1962-1964 June (Box-folder 29:3)
    Includes McCarthy's detailed discussion of his book (attached to letter, October 9, 1962); in-depth editorial notes and questions posed by the editors for McCarthy to answer (attached to letter, October 9, 1962; November 14, 1963; June 2, 17 and 25, 1964); and a reference to his editorial work on a new edition of The Sound and the Fury by William Faulkner (March 4, 1964)
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1964 July-December (Box-folder 29:4)
    Includes a photograph of McCarthy (October 1964).
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1965 (Box-folder 29:5)
    Includes the appraisal of the book by Malcolm Cowley (January 26, 1965).
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1966-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 29:6)
    Includes correspondence and material about his receipt of the William Faulkner Foundation Award for notable first novel for 1965 (February 16, March 1, 3, 9, and 14, April 4, 1966) and a Rockefeller Foundation Grant (March 22, June 3 and July 5, 1966).
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1965 (Box-folder 29:7)
  - Cormac McCarthy- Outer Dark, 1967-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 29:8)
    Includes editing notes (December 22, 1967); an interview in the Maryville-Alcoa Times (February 26, 1971); and reviews (1968-1969, filed at September 29, 1968)
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Stonemason A Play in Five Acts, 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 29:9)
    Typescript Copy, with a letter from Erskine possibly about the play (October 15, 1986).
  - Cormac McCarthy- Suttree, 1971-1986, 1989 (Box-folder 29:10)
    Chiefly reviews (1978-1979, 1989) but also including suggestions from Erskine on ways to improve the book (May 27, 1977); a letter from Shelby Foote (February 10, 1979) with a copy of his letter to the literary editor of the Memphis Press-Scimitar defending McCarthy's book Suttree against a harsh review in the paper
  - Cormac McCarthy- Suttree, 1971 (Box-folder 30:1)
    Early Draft of the novel with the title Harrogate and the Flittermouses.
  - Andre Malraux- Correspondence, 1937, 1952-1963 (Box-folder 30:2)
  - Herman Melville- Correspondence, 1947-1954, 1968 (Box-folder 30:3)
    Concerns the publication of The Complete Stories of Herman Melville edited by Jay Leyda and the possible contents of a Modern Library Herman Melville edition.
  - Michael Mewshaw- Correspondence, 1969-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 30:4)
  - Michael Mewshaw- Earthly Bread, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 30:5)
  - Michael Mewshaw- Earthly Bread, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 30:6)
    Editorial Material and Book Production Material.
  - Michael Mewshaw- Man in Motion- Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 30:7)
    Includes a letter from George Garrett about his former student, Mewshaw (September 26, 1968, attached to a memo dated Oct 14th) and about his own book (March 13, 1969); analysis of an early draft by Steven Aronson (attached to May 20, 1969); Erskine's suggestions about the book (June 18 and October 8, 1969); and Mewshaw's response to both Aronson and Erskine's suggestions (July 10, 1969); and the opinion of William Styron about the book (copy, November 1, 1970)
  - Michael Mewshaw- Man in Motion, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 30:8)
    Editorial and Book Production Material and Reviews.
  - Michael Mewshaw- Reviews and Article by, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 30:9)
  - Michael Mewshaw- Short Stories and Poem, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 30:10)
    Includes Act of Faith, Golden Anniversary, Last of the Beats, and Summer Rain and the poem, Mother and the Wheelchair.
  - Michael Mewshaw- The Toll, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 31:1)
    Includes a synopsis of the book (August 3, 1971); and testimonial letters from Paul Bowles (copy September 30, 1973); George Garrett (attached to January 15, 1974); and Maxine Kumin (January 7, 1974).
  - Michael Mewshaw- Waking Slow- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 31:2)
    Correspondence, including testimonial letters from Anthony Burgess ([November 22], 1971); Walker Percy (March 11, 1972); Robert Penn Warren (copy, December 2, 1971); George Garrett (copy, December 22, 1971).
  - Michael Mewshaw- Waking Slow, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 31:3)
    Editorial and Book Production Material and Reviews, including photographs of Michael Mewshaw, one by Ann Senior for the dust jacket (with letter, July 28, [1971?]).
  - Michael Millgate- Correspondence, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 31:4)
    Includes proposal for a Faulkner handbook (September 2, 1966).
  - Michael Millgate- Thomas Hardy A Biography, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 31:5)
  - Michael Millgate- Thomas Hardy: His Career as a Novelist- Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 31:6)
  - Michael Millgate- Thomas Hardy: His Career as a Novelist, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 31:7)
    Editorial Notes, Synopsis, Book Production Material and Reviews.
  - John O'Hara, ca. 1952-1984 (Box-folder 31:8)
    Articles, Reviews, and Obituaries concerning O'Hara and his work.
  - John O'Hara- Correspondence from or about O'Hara, 1947-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 31:9)
    Includes both copies and originals, mentioning Hellbox (copy April 20, 1947); A Rage to Live (copy, [1949]); From the Terrace and Ourselves to Know (copy, [1958]); letter about being a father of an only daughter (April 21, 1960); list of stories to be included in The Hat on the Bed (May 4, 1963); a photograph of O'Hara's "rolling stock," his antique or classic cars (December 16, 1965); photograph of O'Hara by Alden Whitman, possibly for a dust jacket (November 14, 1967); questions about a car, a Lozier, which O'Hara uses in his latest novel Lovey Childs (September 1, 1969); thanks for helping organize the texts for O'Hara's funeral and memorial service from his daughter, Wylie Holahan (May 21, 1970 and [1970]); letter from Shelby Foote urging Random to publish a big omnibus edition of O'Hara stories (copy, February 23, 1983); and directions and a map to the O'Hara residence (n.d.).
  - John O'Hara- Estate, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 31:10)
    Includes earlier financial and legal documents.
  - John O'Hara- Letters to The New Yorker Staff, 1928-1949, Copies. (Box-folder 31:11)
    Research material left grouped as found.
  - John O'Hara- Letters to The New Yorker Staff, [1958-1967], Copies. (Box-folder 32:1)
  - John O'Hara- Novels- Editorial Notes and Reports, ca. 1934-1972 (Box-folder 32:2)
    Arranged alphabetically by book title, including Appointment in Samaria, Elizabeth Appleton, The Ewings, The Instrument, The Lockwood Concern, Lovey Childs, and Ten North Frederick.
  - John O'Hara- The O'Hara Generation, 1969 (Box-folder 32:3)
    Introduction by Albert Erskine.
  - John O'Hara- Photographs and Random House Memorial, 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 32:4)
  - John O'Hara- Short Stories, ca. 1955-1968 (Box-folder 32:5)
    Forewords by O'Hara, Dust Jackets, and Editorial Notes.
  - John O'Hara- Short Stories, ca. 1943-1970, Some copies. (Box-folder 32:6)
    Print Versions, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - John O'Hara- Short Stories, 1964-1968, n.d., Copies. (Box-folder 32:7)
    Chiefly Typescript Versions with Editorial Markings, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - John O'Hara- Short Stories, n.d., Copies. (Box-folder 32:8)
  - John O'Hara- Short Stories, Novellas, Articles and Plays Inventory, 1970 October 8 (Box-folder 32:9)
  - John O'Hara- Speech- American Academy of Arts and Letters Award, 1964 February 29 (Box-folder 32:10)
  - Eugene O'Neill- Ah, Wilderness, 1933-1940 (Box-folder 32:11)
    Chiefly correspondence and editorial material.
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Correspondence, 1959-1988 (Box-folder 32:12)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Dorsoduro, 1989, English Translation with Murtha Baca- Typed Manuscript with accompanying letter from Pasinetti (1 of 3 folders). (Box-folder 33:1)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Dorsoduro, 1989, English Translation with Murtha Baca- Typed Manuscript (2 of 3 folders). (Box-folder 33:2)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Dorsoduro, 1989, English Translation with Murtha Baca- Typed Manuscript (3 of 3 folders). (Box-folder 33:3)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- From the Academy Bridge- Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 33:4)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- From the Academy Bridge, 1969-1970, Editorial and Book Production Material and Reviews. (Box-folder 33:5)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- The Heirs, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 33:6)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- The Smile on the Face of the Lion- Correspondence, 1963-1966, 1969 (Box-folder 33:7)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- The Smile on the Face of the Lion, 1964-1965, Editorial and Book Production Material and Reviews. (Box-folder 33:8)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Suddenly Tomorrow, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 33:9)
  - P.M. Pasinetti- Venetian Red, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 33:10)
  - David A.Randall- Dukedom Large Enough- Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 34:1)
    Dust Jackets and Reviews.
  - David A.Randall- Dukedom Large Enough, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 34:2)
    Editorial and Book Production Material.
  - Anthony Reinach- The Fastest Game in Town, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 34:3)
    Correspondence, Publicity and Miscellany.
  - Anthony Reinach- The Fastest Game in Town, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 34:4)
  - Karl Shapiro- Adult Book Store, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 34:5)
    Includes correspondence about his lawsuit over a psychiatry article that mentioned his "suicide" (March 20 and April 1, 1975).
  - Karl Shapiro- Bibliography by William White, 1960, Copy. (Box-folder 34:6)
  - Karl Shapiro- The Bourgeois Poet- Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 34:7)
    Includes Erskine's suggestions about the book (March 13 and May 1, 1963).
  - Karl Shapiro- The Bourgeois Poet- Correspondence, 1963-1965, 1969 (Box-folder 34:8)
    Editorial and Book Production Material, including a review in The Hollins Critic (December 1964); correspondence continues with 1964, editorial material, etc. is 1963.
  - Karl Shapiro- Collected Poems: 1948-1978, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 35:1)
  - Karl Shapiro- Correspondence, 1942-3, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 35:2)
    Includes a letter from Evalyn Katz on Shapiro's behalf, asking about how to get copyright to his poems (March 17, 1942); a critique of Person, Place and Thing by Allan Tate in the form of a letter (1943); research on copyright assignments (January 22, Mar 18, and May 27, 1953 and attached); and the publication by the University of Nebraska Press of the Montgomery Lecture on Contemporary Civilization given by Shapiro (May 27, June 5 and 9, 1953)
  - Karl Shapiro- Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 35:3)
    Includes a discussion his idea for a book on the American Jew, involving the concept of "mystery" which resulted from his recent lecture on "the Jewish writer in America" given as a sermon in a synagogue (February 18, 1955). Eventually this was published in poetry form as Poems of a Jew.
  - Karl Shapiro- Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 35:4)
    Concerns the development of Poems of a Jew (September 18, 1956; April 1, 1957 and attached; May 4, 6, October 21, 23, and 31, 1957); questions about the assignment of copyright for poems used in Poems of a Jew (1958 and attached); and mention of Charles E. Feinberg, Detroit, Michigan, who collects his papers (July 21 and 25, 1958).
  - Karl Shapiro- Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 35:5)
    Includes his participation in the Ward Lucas Lecture Series, Carleton College, Northfield, Minnesota (March 30 and May 28, 1964); his separation from Evalyn (attached, January 13, 1966); and Random Houses' refusal of the first draft of his novel, Edsel (November 9, 1966).
  - Karl Shapiro- Correspondence, 1968-1982, 1988 (Box-folder 35:6)
    Includes more discussion on a re-worked version of Edsel, including reader's reports (October 3, 17 and 19, 1968; January 14, February 3, 12, and April 2, 1969); a prospectus for a textbook tentatively called Major Poetics (June 28, 1975); the death of Teri Kovach (July 21, 1982).
  - Karl Shapiro- Essays and Articles, with some Miscellany, 1954-1980 (Box-folder 35:7)
  - Karl Shapiro- In Defense of Ignorance, 1958-1959, 1961 (Box-folder 35:8)
  - Karl Shapiro- Poems: 1940-1953, 1953, 1960 (Box-folder 35:9)
  - Karl Shapiro- The Poetry Wreck: Selected Essays, 1950-1970, 1970-1975, 1978 (Box-folder 35:10)
  - Karl Shapiro- Selected Poems- Correspondence and Reviews, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 36:1)
    Includes difficulties with Bernard Geis, publisher of Edsel (September 15, 1971 and attached; and November 4, 1971; with a review of Edsel, November 28, 1971).
  - Karl Shapiro- Selected Poems, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 36:2)
    Editorial and Book Production Materials.
  - Karl Shapiro- A Telescope for the Emperor,1958 (Box-folder 36:3)
    Typed Manuscript of a Play.
  - Karl Shapiro- White-Haired Lover- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 36:4)
    Includes concerns by the lawyers of Random House over the possibility of libel (May 15, 1967, and attached); notice of his marriage to Teri Kovach (August 7, 1967); and her letter about finances which asks for an advance from Random House (September 29, 1968).
  - Karl Shapiro- White-Haired Lover, 1968 (Box-folder 36:5)
    Editorial and Book Production Materials and Reviews.
  - Karl Shapiro- White-Haired Lover, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 36:6)
    Page Proofs, Dust Jacket, and Printed Poems which were included in the book.
  - Irwin Shaw, 1952, 1964 (Box-folder 36:7)
  - Oliver Statler- Correspondence, 1962-1982 (Box-folder 36:8)
  - Oliver Statler The Japanese Inn- Correspondence, 1956, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 36:9)
  - Oliver Statler- The Japanese Inn- Editorial and Book Production Material, 1960-1961, 1967 (Box-folder 36:10)
  - Oliver Statler- Shimoda Story, [1968] (Box-folder 37:1)
    Author's Notes, Chronology of Events, Postscript, List of Materials Used in the Book and Related.
  - Oliver Statler- Shimoda Story- Correspondence, 1966-1969 March (Box-folder 37:2)
  - Oliver Statler- Shimoda Story- Correspondence, 1969 April-1970 (Box-folder 37:3)
  - Oliver Statler- Shimoda Story, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 37:4)
  - Helen Strauss- A Talent for Luck: An Autobiography, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 37:5)
  - Henry Junior Taylor- The Big Man, [1964] (Box-folder 37:6)
    Editorial Notes.
  - Edward O. Thorp and Sheen T. Kassouf- Beat the Market, 1966 (Box-folder 37:7)
    Articles by Kassouf.
  - Edward O. Thorp and Sheen T. Kassouf- Beat the Market- Correspondence, 1966-1969, 1973 (Box-folder 37:8)
  - Edward O. Thorp and Sheen T. Kassouf- Beat the Market, 1967 (Box-folder 37:9)
  - Edward O. Thorp and Sheen T. Kassouf- Beat the Market, 1966-1967 January (Box-folder 38:1)
    Editorial and Book Production Materials. Corrections and Changes.
  - Edward O. Thorp and Sheen T. Kassouf- Beat the Market, 1967 February-1968 July (Box-folder 38:2)
  - Robert Penn Warren- Brother to Dragons: A Tale in Verse and Voices- A New Version, 1975 (Box-folder 38:3)
    Annotated Typescript with letters from Erskine (July 7, 1975) and Warren (July 21, 1975).
  - Robert Penn Warren- Envelopes, 1964 April-September (Box-folder 38:4)
    Envelopes (empty) addressed in his hand to Albert Erskine, numbered 1-6.
  - Robert Penn Warren- Flood: A Romance of Our Time, [1964] (Box-folder 38:5)
  - Robert Penn Warren- A Robert Penn Warren Reader, 1987 (Box-folder 38:6)
    Page proof of Editor's Note by Albert Erskine. Eudora Welty-Correspondence (general correspondence not pertaining to one of her books published by Random House has been placed in Series IV, Box 42; correspondence just about the production of her books is in this series).
  - Eudora Welty- The Eye of the Story, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 38:7)
    There are also many references to this book in her correspondence file in Box 42.
  - Eudora Welty- Losing Battles- Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 38:8)
    There are also some references to this book in her correspondence file in Box 42.
  - Eudora Welty- Losing Battles- Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 38:9)
    Includes Welty's concerns over the remaindering of her book and its not being back-listed in Random's catalog (1973, throughout)
  - Eudora Welty- Losing Battles, 1969-1970, 1972 (Box-folder 38:10)
  - Eudora Welty- Losing Battles, [1969-1970] (Box-folder 38:11)
  - Eudora Welty- Miscellany, 1969-1992 (Box-folder 39:1)
  - Eudora Welty- One Time, One Place, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 39:2)
  - Eudora Welty- The Optimist's Daughter, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 39:3)
  - Martin J. Whitman and Martin Shubik- The Aggressive Conservative Investor, 1977-1979, 1983 (Box-folder 39:4)
- Series IV: Correspondence and Personal Files
  - Biographical Information, 1944-1966 (Box-folder 39:5)
  - Book Club Lists, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 39:6)
  - Correspondence- A, 1956-1972 (Box-folder 39:7)
    Includes: R.P. Adams, Samuel Hopkins Adams, William H. Amos, and Robert C. Axtmann.
  - Correspondence- B, 1937-1990 (Box-folder 39:8)
    Includes Isabel Bailey (permission to use letters from Katherine Anne Porter to Erskine in Letters of Katherine Anne Porter, 1989-1990); John Bainbridge; Howard Baker (praise for Erskine's work with his book, Introduction to Tragedy, while at the LSU Press, 1939); calling card of Luigi Barzini; Anne Baxter (her visit to London and thanks for a book of poems, 1958); Warren Beck; Saul Bellow (requests several books for his Britannica article reviewing the year in literature, 1962); Robert L. Bernstein; Tom Bethell; R.P. Blackmur (his poem printed in The Southern Review, 1937); Henning Branner (proposal for an automobile book, 1962); William Brinkley (reference in his letter and editorial fact sheet concerning his book, The Fun House, 1959 and 1961); Paul Brooks; and John Burt.
  - Correspondence- Cleanth Brooks and Edith Amy ("Tinkum") Brooks, 1940-1986 (Box-folder 39:9)
    Includes a newsy letter about persons connected to The Southern Review and the Louisiana State University just after Erskine left for a new job (February 28, [1941?]); personal correspondence with the Erskine family and a memorial service program for Edith Brooks.
  - Correspondence- Matthew J. Bruccoli, 1969-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 39:10)
    Includes several articles by him.
  - Correspondence- Kenneth Burke, 1939-1943, n.d. (Box-folder 39:11)
    Includes letters about the publication of The Philosophy of Literary Form: Studies in Symbolic Action, Louisiana State University Press (1940); and the relative success of his earlier books (December 21, 19390.
  - Correspondence- C, 1935-1993 (Box-folder 40:1)
    Includes John Carr; Frank Cayce; Bennett Cerf (social telegram, 1966); James Cerruti; Jac Chambliss; David M. Clay; Mr. Cleary; Florence Codman (translation of Paul Valery's essay, July 1, 1938); Peggy Cole (difficulties with her writing and application for Guggenheim Fellowship,1951-1952); Marta Cohn; George Core; Richard Hauer Costa; W.T. Couch (advice for Erskine about the publishing world, July 29, 1940); Malcolm Cowley (reference to the bombing of Pearl Harbor and questions about the progress of his book, The Dry Season, December 7, 1941); Joan Crane; Ollinger Crenshaw; Richard Curry; and Thomas W. Cutrer (requests permission to quote letters from Erskine about The Southern Review (1983).
  - Correspondence- Ellen R. Campbell, 1934-1938, n.d. (Box-folder 40:2)
    Family friend from Memphis, Tennessee, who writes news about his mother and sister.
  - Correspondence- D, 1940-1987 (Box-folder 40:3)
    Includes Jack Dalton; Silvio D'Amico; James H. Daughdrill, Jr.; George Bindley Davidson; Gustav Davidson; A. Grove Day; Douglas Day; Bonamy Dobree; Dean Donaldson; Scott and Wylie Doughty; and Donald P. Duclos.
  - Correspondence- Donald Davidson, 1937-1939, 1962 (Box-folder 40:4)
    Faculty advisor from Vanderbilt, who writes about Erskine's thesis concerning Marxist criticism (1937-1939).
  - Correspondence- E through F, 1938-1971 (Box-folder 40:5)
    Includes Arieh Eilan; Leslie A. Fieldler; Irving Fiske; John Gould Fletcher (lists his complaints against The Southern Review and its treatment of him, January 22, 1938); Edmund Fuller; and Robert G. Fuller.
  - Correspondence- G, 1961-1991 (Box-folder 40:6)
    Includes Rabbi Israel J. Gerber; Dr. Marvin H. Gewirtz; Rabbi Roland B. Gittelsohn; U.N. Representative Goldberg (invitation); Howard B. Gotlieb; Julie Grau (with explanatory note by Julian [Pace?]); Gerald J. Gross; and Annick Le Guerer.
  - Correspondence- Frances Greer, 1937 (Box-folder 40:7)
    Personal letters about her trip to Hollywood, California.
  - Correspondence- James A. Grimshaw, Jr., 1984-1992 (Box-folder 40:8)
    Chiefly about asking Erskine to serve as a member of the editorial panel of the Papers of the Arkansas Philological Association 80th birthday tribute to Robert Penn Warren (1984-1986); and a copy of Grimshaw's Texas Voices Presentation on Texas the novel by James A. Michener (April 14, 1986 attached).
  - Correspondence- H, 1942-1992 (Box-folder 40:9)
    Includes: Robert L. Hagin; David A. Hallman (anecdotes concerning Andrew Lytle); S.I. Hayakawa (encloses a speech, Mass Media and Family Communications by Hayakawa, 1968); John P. Hayes (biographer of James A. Michener); Richard L. Helburn; John Hersey (copy of letter to Hersey about large print books, September 3, 1969; and personal note July 2, 1992); Regina Lawrence Hersh; James Hinkle (concerning glossaries for each of William Faulkner's books); Robert Hanks Hivnor; Glenn Hodges; H.R. Holzner; Ann Hulbert; J.T. Hunter; and Henry Hurt.
  - Correspondence- I through K, 1939-1986 (Box-folder 41:1)
    Includes: William Inge; Edward J. Irwin; Willis D. Jacobs; Marc Jaffe; David Jarovsky (The First Stage of Michurinism attached; George Jessel; John K. Jessup; Albert M. Johnson, Librarian of Southwestern at Memphis; Warren R. Johnston; Willmoore Kendall; Greta Kilburn-Meurs; and Bertha Krantz (personal letter, n.d.)
  - Correspondence- L through M, 1935-1981 (Box-folder 41:2)
    Includes: Mildred Layne; Roger Leclere; Nathan F. Leopold; Jay [Leyda]; John Longley; Zoe Lyon; Andrew Lytle (describes his work and life routines at the Cornsilk Farm (August 22, 1935), writes that he will end his association with The Sewanee Review with the fall issue to allow more time for his own work (August 1, 1943), and arranges to meet Erskine and his wife (March 10, 1945); Joshua Manning; Martin Manulis (interest in books for use in motion pictures and films); Dr. Peter M. Marcuse; Linton Massey; Mildred Marmur; B.C. McClure; Ken McCormick; Lawrence Menkin; George Milburn (comments on The Southern Review, August 20, 1935, his thankfulness that Robert Penn Warren has accepted his story for the Fall issue and appreciation for his encouragement, September 2, 1935, and explanation for why he needed payment as soon as possible (November 12, 1935).
    Correspondence- L through M continues with: Arthur Miller (apologizes for not answering Erskine's phone call but notes he has finished a screenplay that he had worked on for a year, July 11, 1950); John A. Miller; F.T. Mitchell; Nancy Mitford; Samuel Holton Monk and Wanda Caton Monk (references to The Southern Review and Erskine's marriage, 1937-1938); Ray Morgan; Edita Morris (attempt to recover her book of short stories Birth of an Old Lady which she had loaned to his wife (September 5, 1940); and Wright Morris (humorous discussion of cars, March 19, 1948).
  - Correspondence- Howard Nemerov, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 41:3)
    Includes postal cards with chess moves indicated (1948); reader's critique of two books of his poems (March 15, 1949; April 3, 1950); reference to his "dirty old first novel" [The Melodramatists?] (January 13, 1949; July 23, 1951); comments about his new book of poems ([Guide to the Ruins?] June 6, 1949); difficulties in writing a novel when occupied by a full-time job (December 16, 1950); and a copy of his poem, Central Park (n.d.)
  - Correspondence- O through Q, 1937-1988 (Box-folder 41:4)